SEENA RAVEENDRAN Accountant-AP/AR/General/VAT

Email: senaraveendran@gmail.com

Mobile: 055-6358131 Address: Al Qusais, Dubai



CAREER SUMMARY

Analytical and meticulous Professional Accountant with 15 + years of UAE experience in Accounting, Strong work ethic and commitment to integrity and accurate record keeping. Eager to join a team and help improve an organization's financial focus.

PROVEN JOB ROLE -

ALTAYER GROUP, DUBAI - Finance Shared Services-

April 2021 to Dec. 2022 -Accountant-Payables -Contract

TOPROCK INTERIORS L.L.C, DUBAI, U.A.E

November 2013 -February 2021

Senior Accountant (payables / Receivables)

AL BOSHIA TECHNICCAL SERVICES L.L.C, DUBAI, U.A.E

September 2009 - October 2013 - General Accountant

MAJID AL FUTTAIM (MAF) PROPERTIES, DUBAI, U.A.E

December 2007 - April 2009- Accountant -Payables.

AL HAFFAR GENERAL MAINTENANCE, DUBAI, U.A.E

January 2006 - November 2007-Accountant cum Administrator

JOB RESPONSINILITIES:

- Proper handling of accounts receivables Prepares, posts, verifies, and records customer payments and transactions related to accounts receivable. Creates error-free invoices according to company practices; submits invoices to clients.
- Proper Handling of Accounts Payables .Created tracking reports and worksheets for improved handling of accounts payable.. Make the payments to the suppliers as per the credit period to maintain relationship with the supplier and to get the material on time for smooth running of the project.
- Preparation of sub-contractor payment on timely basis after verification of proper documents and certifications
- Petty cash Management -Handling of petty cash to meet the general and operational expenses of the company.

SKILLS

- Al Ameen Accounting
- Pact -ERP Accounting software
- o Tally ERP 9
- JD Edwards
- QuickBooks
- Zoho books
- o Peach Tree
- o Payroll Software
- MS office
- GAAP
- o IFRS

AREASOF EXPERIENCE

- Accounts Receivable
- Accounts Payable
- o Inventory Control
- o Bank Reconciliation
- VAT Filing
- Payroll
- o WPS
- Procurement Process
- Letter of Credit
- General Ledger

EDUCATION

Master of Commerce Kerala University, India

Bachelor of Commerce

Calicut University, India

Higher Diploma in Co-Operation

Calicut University , India

Type Writing English (Lower)

Office Automation
With Financial Accounting

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Indian Civil Status: Married Visa: Spouse Visa Driving License: UAE

SPECIAL STRENGTHS:

Positive attitude
Commitment towards the goal
Dedication towards the work
Self-acquired Knowledge
Detail Oriented.
Team Leadership skills
Multi-tasking
Analytical &problem Solving

Languages:

English Hindi Malayalam Tamil

Availability: Immediately

- Intercompany reconciliation to find out the difference if any, make the adjustment entries accordingly.
- Posting of daily financial transactions in the accounting system.
- MIS Reporting
- Created and developed an accounting system that has helped to produce accurate financial reports. Preparation of Financial statements
- Prepare man power allocation on monthly basis to recognize the cost of the project
- Payroll Management -Adept with calculating staff payroll, leave salary and end of service benefits and payroll transfer through WPS.
- Responsible for daily banking activities such as deposits, withdrawals, issuance of Cheques. Monitored daily bank balances through Internet banking and prepared daily Bank Balance statement. Liaising with Bank for Facilities, maintaining healthy relationship with banks
- Budgeting and Project costing, Follow up and recovery of retention money, withheld by different customers for their various projects.
- Monitoring the daily Purchase booking, Invoicing, Journals, Debit/Credit notes and other accounts related transactions .Verify purchase requisitions, obtain necessary approvals before preparing LPO, Preparation of POs
- Managing Bank Guarantee, Performance Bond and Letter of Credits
- Bank Reconciliation.
- Preparation of cash flow statement for the proper utilization of funds.
- General Ledger Management Prepare general ledger entries as a part of month end financial close processes including accruals and prepaid expenses.
- Vat Filing- Compute taxes and prepare VAT returns. Filing VAT and payment of VAT. VAT Business Process and control of accounting for VAT .Checking VAT Reports in line with VAT rules and update the reports as and when required/Management of VAT accounting balances VAT return /Reconciliation of VAT return.
- Monthly closing of accounts and preparation of reports such as Trial Balance, Bank reconciliation. Aged debtors and creditors list, Monthly sales report, Monthly Expenses report, etc.
- Inventory Management.
- Handle internal and external audit work support to solve the queries and providing necessary documents. Co-ordination with External Auditors
- Experienced with all aspects of financial and management accounting with ERP system.

References available upon requests

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Mrs. Seena Raveendran Al Qusais, Dubai